The Lullaby is a horror film directed by Darrell James Roodt.
Returning to her home town, overwhelmed by the birth of her firstborn,
nineteen-year-old Chloe van Heerden tries to come to terms with motherhood.
Despite the support from her own mother, Chloe struggles with
the demands of caring for a newborn child.
The incessant crying of her baby, the growing sense of guilt
and paranoia send her into a dark depression.
With a heightened urge to protect her son, she sees danger everywhere.
Chloe van Heerden, played by Reine Swart.
Adam Hess, played by Deanre Reiners.
Ruby van Heerden, played by Thandi Puren.
Dr. Timothy Reed, played by Brandon Auret.
Midwife, played by Dorothy Ann Gould.
Young Chloe, played by Shayla-Rae McFarlane.
The Lullaby (also known as Siembamba) is a 2017 South African horror film directed by
Darrell Roodt and co-produced by Samuel Frauenstein and Andre Frauenstein Snr.
The film stars Reine Swart with Thandi Puren, Brandon Auret, Deànré
Reiners, and Dorothy Ann Gould in supporting roles.
The film tells the story of 19-year-old mom, Chloe van Heerden, who struggled to dealing with her super
critical mother, Ruby, where she finally ends in a paranoia that sends Chloe into a dark depression.
This is the first purely South African film production
to release theatrically in the USA.
Rotten Tomatoes ranked the film as the 17th Best Horror Movie for 2018.
The film was shot in and around Pretoria, Gauteng, South Africa.
It premiered at the 2017 South African Horrorfest Film Festival.
The film explores themes of mother, baby, single mother, postpartum depression.
The tone is dark.